Guide to the Stanford University, University Committee on Minority Issues, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, University Committee on Minority Issues, records
1986-1989
SC0363
Stanford University. University Committee on Minority Issues.
17.5 Linear feet
Records include correspondence, reports, surveys, questionnaires, interviews, tables, articles, brochures, clippings, audio tapes, and other items pertaining to minority students, faculty, and staff at Stanford University, compiled from University documents, reports, and data files and from interviews and surveys with students, faculty, and staff conducted by SRI International and Pacific Management Systems.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1989.
Information about Access
Restricted access: for more information, contact the Archives and Manuscripts Librarian.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The University Committe on Minority Issues was established by the President and Provost in October 1987 in response to a demand by the Rainbow Agenda (a coalition of minority groups) to explore the critical concerns of minority students, faculty, and staff at Stanford University.
Description of the Collection
Records include correspondence, reports, surveys, questionnaires, interviews, tables, articles, brochures, clippings, audio tapes, and other items pertaining to minority students, faculty, and staff at Stanford University, compiled from University documents, reports, and data files and from interviews and surveys with students, faculty, and staff conducted by SRI International and Pacific Management Systems.
Access Terms
De Necochea, Fernando; Pacific Management Systems.; SRI International; Stanford University. University Committee on Minority Issues.; Minorities --Education (Higher).; Minorities --Employment.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-1989-096
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 1-5, Undated (Box 1)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 6, Committee Correspondence, Undated (Box 1)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 7, University Correspondence, Undated (Box 1)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 7B, University Correspondence, Undated (Box 1)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Working Group Rosters, Undated (Box 1)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9A, 1-15, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 2)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9B, 16-41, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 2)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9C, 42-60, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 2)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9D, 61-100, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 2)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9E, 101-110, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 3)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9F, 111-120, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 3)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9G, 121-150, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 3)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9H, 151-169, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 3)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9, Confidential Materials, Undated (Box 3)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9I, 170-183, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 4)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9J, 184-207, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 4)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 9K, 208-216, Stanford Information, Undated (Box 4)
  - UCMI Master Binder, DOSA Response to UCMI Drafts, Undated (Box 4)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 10A, 1-33, External Information, Undated (Box 5)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 10B, 34-60, External Information, Undated (Box 5)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 10C, 61-76, External Information, Undated (Box 5)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 11A, Newspaper Clippings, 1986 Nov-1987 Dec (Box 5)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 11B, Newspaper Clippings, 1988 Jan-Jun (Box 5)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 11C, Newspaper Clippings, 1988 Jul-1989 Jan (Box 6)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 11D, Newspaper Clippings, 1989 Jan-Mar (Box 6)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12A, Committee Reports, Undated (Box 6)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12B, Committee Reports, Undated (Box 6)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12C, Committee Reports, Undated (Box 6)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12D, Committee Reports, Undated (Box 7)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12E, Committee Reports, Undated (Box 7)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12F, Committee Reports, Undated (Box 7)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12G, Committee Reports, Undated (Box 7)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12H, Final Reports-1, Undated (Box 8)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12H, Final Reports-2, Undated (Box 8)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12, Drafts of Final Report (TOC-Undergrad), Undated (Box 8)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Formation of Committee (Charge/Correspondence/Minutes), Undated (Box 8)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Study of Student Life at Stanford (Survey), Undated (Box 8)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Interim Report-1, Undated (Box 9)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Interim Report-2, Undated (Box 9)
  - UCMI Master Binder, SRI Research-1, Undated (Box 9)
  - UCMI Master Binder, SRI Research-2, Undated (Box 9)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Pacific Management System Studies (PMS), Undated (Box 10)
  - UCMI Master Binder, PMS Research Student Interviews-1, Undated (Box 10)
  - UCMI Master Binder, PMS Research Student Interviews-2, Undated (Box 10)
  - UCMI Master Binder, PMS Research Student Interviews-3, Undated (Box 10)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12, Drafts of Final Report (Stu Lif-Staff), Undated (Box 10)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Section 12, Drafts of Final Report (Undergrad/Grad), Undated (Box 11)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Curriculum Working Group, Undated (Box 11)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Student Life, Undated (Box 11)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Faculty Working Group, Undated (Box 11)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Staff Working Group, Undated (Box 11)
  - UCMI Master Binder, Undergrad/Grad Working Group, Undated (Box 11)
  - UCMI Full Committee Meetings, 1987 Oct 27-1989 Feb 28; 12.1-12.38; 38 audiocassette(s) (Box 12)
  - UCMI Full Committee Retreats, 1988 Apr 9-1989 Jan 8; 13.1-13.25; 25 audiocassette(s) (Box 13)
  - UCMI Dorm Outreach, Forums and Special Meeting, 1988 Jan-May 4; 14.1-14.10; 10 audiocassette(s) (Box 14)
  - UCMI Dorm Outreach Programs, 1988 Apr-May; 15.1-15.15; 15 audiocassette(s) (Box 15)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1989-111
  - Student Survey, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - University Affirmative Action Reports, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - UCMI Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Working group, Notes on subcommittee meetings, memos, directory, "UCMI Charge"
  - Rosse Report, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - UCMI Interim Report, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - UCMI Final Report, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Questionnaires and Surveys: Engineering School, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Questionnaires and Surveys: Undergraduates, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Questionnaires and Surveys: Law School, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Questionnaires and Surveys: Medical School, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Questionnaires and Surveys: Business School, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Questionnaires and Surveys: Faculty/Staff, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Studies: Survey, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Studies: Admissions Data, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Studies: Drafts, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Studies: Tables, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Graduate Studies: Stats, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Graduate Studies: Other Graduate Schools, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - News clippings on UCMI, Minority, Racism, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Articles, newsletters, brochures on minority, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Other institutions' plans for Affirmative Action, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Review of the California Master Plan Eureka Project (financial aid), Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - High School Data, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)